

PHD PHYSICIST · AI SCIENTIST

Carrer del Roser, 27, 2nd - 08004 - Barcelona (Spain)

□ (+34) 658 87 0927 | ■ leax.fis@gmail.com | 😭 leaxp.github.io | 🖫 GitHub | 🛅 LinkedIn

About Me

I am PhD physicist and AI researcher with interdisciplinary experience along Europe and south America. I have a PhD degree in physics from my hometown university, south of Brazil, carried with a 2 years exchange program at Heidelberg University in Germany. My first post-doc I did at Oxford University in United Kingdom. Currently I am based in Spain, working at ICFO - institute of photonics sciences developing deep learning computer vision techniques applied to super-resolution microscopy and single molecule localization.

Personal Interests: Music (and play), Cinema, Sculpture, Museums, Dogs, Running, Hiking, Skating, Beach, Eating Good, Drinking Good (Specialty Coffee and Craft Beers), Rural Tourism.

Skills

Programming Python, C++, LabView, MatLab, HTML, CSS, Flask, Django

Databases MySQL, MongoDB, Amazon Web Service, Gogle Cloud Service

Machine Learning tools PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, OpenCV

Machine Learning Methods U-Net, Faster R-CNN, Autoencoders, XGBoost, ConvNets, PCA, t-SNE

Experience ____

ICFO - Institute of Photonic Sciences

Castelldefels (Barcelona), Spain

2016 - Current



POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER

- Molecular Nanophotonics Group Prof. Niek van Hulst
- Deep Learning single molecule localization
- Single molecule fluorescence
- · Scanning microscopy

Oxford, United Kingdom 2014 - 2016



Oxford University

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

- Kukura Lab Prof. Phillip Kukura
- Wide-field microscopy
- Ultrafast spectroscopy
- Biomolecular dynamics

Education _



Heidelberg University

Heidelberg, Germany

2011 - 2013

PhD in Physics

- Motzkus Group Prof. Marcus Motzkus
- Vibrational microscopy
- Coherent Raman spectroscopy
- Tissues and carbon nanotubes studies

UFRGS

UFRGS (Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul)

Porto Alegre, Brazil

2009 - 2014

M.Sc. and PhD in Physics

- PhD Thesis Multiplex CARS applied to carbon nanotubes and brain tissues
 - Laboratory instrumentation
 - Physics and Optics fundamentals

Deep Learning Localization Super-Resolutiom Microscopy

ICFO (2020)

OBJECT DETECTION FOR SINGLE MOLECULE LOCALIZATION IMAGE RECONSTRUCTION

IMC cells segmentation

Ai.Vali (2019)

CELLS SEGMENTATION OF IMAGING MASS CYTOMETRY IMAGES

Endoscopy Image Classification

Ai.Vali (2019)

ENDOSCOPY TISSUES CLASSIFICATION WITH DEEP LEARNING

Properties Price Prediction

SharpestMinds (2017)

PREDICTION OF THE SALE PRICE OF PROPERTIES IN LONDON

Wide-Field Detected Fourier Transform CARS Microscopy

Scientifc Reports (2016)

DOI:10.1038/srep37516

Sub-10 fs Time-Resolved Vibronic Optical Microscopy

ALEX SOARES DUARTE, CHRISTOPH SCHNEDERMANN, PHILIPP KUKURA

J. Physical Chemistry Letters (2016)

CHRISTOPH SCHNEDERMANN, JONG MIN LIM, TORSTEN WENDE, **ALEX S. DUARTE**, LIMENG NI, QIFEI GU, ADITYA SADHANALA, AKSHAY RAO, AND PHILIPP KUKURA

DOI:10.1021/acs.jpclett.6b02387

Barrierless Photoisomerization of 11-cis Retinal Protonated Schiff Base in Solution

Journal of American Chemistry
Society **(2015)**

GIOVANNI BASSOLINO, TINA SOVDAT, **ALEX SOARES DUARTE**, JONG MIN LIM, CHRISTOPH SCHNEDERMANN, MATZ LIEBEL, BARBARA ODELL, TIMOTHY D. W. CLARIDGE, STEPHEN P. FLETCHER AND PHILIPP KUKURA

DOI:10.1002/10.1021/jacs.5b06492

Chemical imaging of lignocellulosic biomass by CARS microscopy

Journal of Biophotonics (2014)

Christoph Pohling, Christian Brackmann, **Alex Duarte**, Tiago Buckup, Annika Enejder and Marcus Motzkus

DOI:10.1002/jbio.201300052

Mapping impurity of single-walled carbon nanotubes in bulk samples with multiplex coherent anti-stokes Raman microscopy

Nano Letters (2013)

ALEX S. DUARTE, JEAN REHBINDER, RICARDO R. B. CORREIA, TIAGO BUCKUP AND MARCUS MOTZKUS

DOI:10.1021/nl304371x

